只能这么办
It's the only way.
别人不能知道
No one else knows.
你会告诉他们吗
You gonna tell 'em?
完事后再说
Not till after.
今天必须动手  要安静利落
We have to do it today. It has to be quiet.
你有计划吗
You got a plan?
就说我们要跟她谈谈
We tell her we need to talk.
远离其他人
Away from the others.
我们不是这样的人
Just ain't us, man.
对  的确不是
No. No, it isn't.
这样做
We do this,
能息事宁人
we avoid a fight.
避免死伤
No one else dies.
好吧
All right.
我们还需要一个人帮忙
We need someone else.
我去跟他说
I'll talk to him.
我去
I'll do it.
-我和你一起去  -不
- I'll go with you. - No.
我一个人去
Just me.
我只是搜刮搜刮
Just looking for a little vacation.
我吸过最好的毒品就藏在床垫里
Best dope I ever had was in a mattress.
一无所获
Nothing.
这个监狱一定很无趣
This place must have been no fun at all.
我们需要你帮忙
We need your help.
你知道自己以前为何
Do you even know why you do the things you do?
犯下累累恶行吗
The choices you make?
如果我们把米琼恩交给总督
If we give the Governor Michonne,
他们就放弃进攻
Woodbury stands down.
我也不想  可这是不得已为之
I don't like it, but it's what needs to be done.
我们得偷偷地干  所以要你帮忙
We need to make it quiet. We need your help with that.
你没告诉其他人对吧
You ain't told any of the others, huh?
只有赫谢尔  达里尔  还有你
Just Hershel, Daryl and you.
都是核心人物啊
The inner circle.
我真荣幸
I'm honored.
跟你说啊
You know,
以前我和总督行动时
when we'd go out on runs,
他杀人都是砸碎脑袋
he'd bash somebody's skull,
割开喉咙
slash somebody's throat,
他总说  "永远别浪费子弹"
and he'd say, "Never waste a bullet."
但我知道那只是他嗜杀的借口
I always thought it was just an excuse.
你去吧
You go on.
把那个姑娘交给他
Give him that girl.
他不会杀她
He ain't gonna kill her, you know.
他只会折磨她
He's just gonna do things to her.
可能挖出她的一只眼睛
Probably take out one of her eyes.
或者两只都挖出来
Both of 'em, most likely.
你就为了渺茫的机会
You'd let that happen
让这种事发生吗
for a shot?
你真是冷酷无情  友好警官
You're cold as ice, Officer Friendly.
得用金属线绑她
You're gonna need wire,
不能用普通绳子
not rope.
用金属线  她咬不断
Wire. Nothing she could chew through.
知道吗
You know something?
你说得对
You're right.
我不知道自己为何做出恶行
I don't know why I do the things I do.
从来都不知道
Never did.
我自己都不了解自己
I'm a damn mystery to me.
但是我了解你  瑞克
But I know you, Rick.
是的  我很了解你
Yeah, I thought a lot about you.
你没有做这事的勇气
You ain't got the spine for it.
我们得在中午前把她送给总督
We need to get her to the Governor by noon.
《行尸走肉》
过来  来这边
Hey! Come on! Over here!
-快来  -快过来
- Hey! Come on! - Over here!
这边
Hey! Right here!
快过来
Over here!
-快来  -这里  这里
- Come on! - Here! Here!
过来
Come on!
快点  咱们走
Come on, let's go.
他们下次再想闯进来
They try to drive up to the gate again,
爆胎也许能阻止他们
maybe some blown tires will stop them.
-好主意  -是米琼恩的主意
- That's a good idea. - It was Michonne's.
我们没必要打败他们
We don't have to win.
我们只要让他们知道
We just have to make their getting at us
攻击我们是得不偿失的
more trouble than it's worth.
走吧
Let's go.
不可能
Ain't no way.
怎么了
What?
没事
Nothing.
有什么事吗
What happened here?
有威士忌吗
We got any whiskey?
算了吧  伏特加也凑合
Hell, I'd even drink vodka.
去死吧  莫尔
Go to hell, Merle.
你跟我们一起吗
Are you with us?
当然了
Sure.
我不是说住在一起
I'm not talking about occupying the same space.
我问你跟我们一伙吗
Are you with us?
我跟弟弟共进退
I'm here for my brother.
他跟我们共进退
Well, he's here for us.
现在不该喝酒
It's not time to do shots.
赶紧选边吧
It's time to pick a damn side.
你和在营地时不太一样
You ain't like you was back in the camp--
那时你怯怯懦懦
a little mouse running around,
杯弓蛇影
scared of her own shadow.
我那时活在丈夫的阴影下
It wasn't my shadow, it was my husband's.
你看起来什么都不怕了
Well, you don't seem scared of nothing anymore.
没错
I'm not.
变化真大
You're a late bloomer.
也许你也能变
Maybe you are, too.
你看见莫尔了吗
You seen Merle around?
他跟你说对不起了吗
He say he was sorry yet?
他确实对不起你
'Cause he is.
他会补偿你的
He's gonna make it right.
我会逼着他
I'm gonna make him.
总会有办法的
There's got to be a way.
只需要一点点宽容
Just needs to be a little forgiveness is all.
他把我绑在椅子上
He tied me to a chair,
毒打我  把一个行尸扔进屋子里
beat me, and threw a walker in the room.
这个也许我能释怀
Maybe I could call it even.
但他
But he--
他把玛姬带到一个恐吓她的人面前
he took Maggie to a man who terrorized her,
羞辱她
humiliated her.
我在乎她比在乎我多
I care more about her than I care about me.
莫尔
Merle.
你在吗
You down here?
莫尔
Merle.
小弟
Hey, little brother.
你在干什么
What the hell?
我正要喊你呢
I was just about to holler back at ya.
你在这下面干什么
What you doing down here?
看看这里有没有冰毒
Just looking for a little crystal meth.
好吧  我知道
Yeah, yeah, I know.
现在风平浪静
Shit will mess my life up
吸毒会毁了大好人生  对吧
when everything is going so sweet, right?
你跟瑞克谈了吗
You talk to Rick yet?
是的  当然  我加入
Yeah. Oh, yeah. I'm in.
但是
But, uh,
他的心肠做不了这种事
he ain't got the stomach for it.
他会改变主意  你懂的  对吗
He's gonna buckle. You know that, right?
是的
Yeah.
他想怎样  随他去吧
If he does, he does.
你希望他改主意吗
You want him to?
他说什么就是什么
Whatever he says goes.
兄弟
Man.
你到底
Do you even possess
有没有种啊  老弟
a pair of balls, little brother?
胆子都被吃了吗
Are they even attached?
你还有主见吗
I mean, if they are, do they belong to you?
你曾称那样的人为随波逐流者
You used to call people like that sheep.
你到底怎么了
What happened to you?
那你呢  对格伦和玛姬
What happened with you and Glenn
做出那种事
and Maggie?
那不算什么
I've done worse.
你得长大了
You need to grow up.
现在世道不同了
Things are different now.
你们把我当恶魔
Your people look at me like I'm the devil...
因为我绑架了那对情侣  是吗
grabbing up those lovebirds like that, huh?
你们将要做的事  跟我毫无差别
Now y'all want to do the same damn thing I did--
绑架某人然后交给总督
snatch someone up and deliver them to the Governor,
跟我一模一样
just like me.
没错
Yeah.
为了活命  人什么都能做出来
People do what they got to do or they die.
不靠别人  就无法生存  兄弟
Can't do things without people anymore, man.
也许他们需要我这样的人
Maybe these people need somebody like me around, huh?
帮他们做下流勾当
Do their dirty work.
唱白脸
The bad guy.
就这么简单
Yeah, maybe that's how it is now, huh?
你对此怎么看
How does that hit you?
我只想哥在我身边
I just want my brother back.
别在这里烦我  兄弟
Get out of here, man.
"你不要惧怕
"Thou shalt not be afraid
黑夜的惊骇
for the terror by night.
或是白日飞的箭
Nor for the arrow that flieth by day.
也不必恐惧
Nor for the pestilence
黑夜蔓延的瘟疫
that walketh in darkness.
或是午间
Nor for the destruction
灭人的毒病
that wasteth at noonday.
纵有千人仆倒在你旁边
1,000 shall fall at thy side
万人仆倒在你右边
and 10,000 at thy right hand.
这灾却不得临近你
But it shall not come nigh thee.
你惟有亲眼观看
Only with thine eyes shalt thou behold
见恶人遭报
and see the reward of the wicked.
他必救你脱离
Surely He shall deliver thee
捕鸟人的网罗
from the snare of the fowler
与瘟疫的毒害"
and from the noisome pestilence."
你没在那里
You're not there.
她是幻觉
She's not there.
"他必用自己的翎毛遮蔽你
"He shall cover thee
而你要投靠在他的翅膀底下
and under His wings shalt thou trust.
祸患必不临到你
There shall no evil befall thee.
灾害也绝不挨近你的帐棚"
Neither shall any plague come nigh thy dwelling."
你还好吗
You okay?
为了你们俩的安全
What I wouldn't do
我愿意做任何事
to keep you two safe.
瑞克
Rick?
你要做的那件事...
What you're about to do--
我不能那样做
I can't.
我也不会那么做
I won't.
-在哪里  -拐角处
- So where is it? - Around the corner.
我们先清理行尸
We got to clear some walkers,
然后让其他人过来修补
then get the others down here to barricade it.
这样的漏洞等于给总督送上请柬
A breach like this could be an open invitation to the Governor.
他可没那么精明
He's not much for subtlety.
你想试试吗
You want to take your chances?
总督跟瑞克定下协议
Governor made Rick an offer.
交出你  然后和平共处
Turn you over and we all give peace a chance.
我同意  这个决定令他会良心不安
I agree with you, though. He would have blinked.
但你不会
But not you.
我对你一向很坦诚
I'm being straight with you.
刚才是你骗我过去
You were straight when you led me into the tombs.
好吧  也许我没那么坦诚
Okay, maybe I wasn't straight.
你还用袋子蒙住我的头
You put a bag over my head.
我能下狠心
I got it done.
他不行
He wouldn't have.
继续走
Keep moving.
他是那种会回到屋顶救我的人
He was a guy that came back for me on that rooftop.
脏活还得靠我
It's all on me.
你知道吗
You know?
我猜这才是我回到那里的原因
I figure that's why I was back there in the first place.
干其他人做不了的坏事
Do the dirty work.
借刀一用
May I?
不说话就是答应了
I'll take that as a yes.
你知道吗  我以为你会逃跑呢
You know what? I'd figured you would have run.
走之前我得拿回我的刀
Wanted my sword back before I get away.
想得不错啊
It may go down that way.
但如果我是你
But if I were you,
我不会抱太大的希望
I wouldn't get my hopes up.
走
Move.
行动取消  我们跟总督硬碰硬
It's off. We'll take our chances.
之前的决定不一定是错误的
I'm not saying it was the wrong call,
但这绝对是正确选择
but this is definitely the right one.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我找不到莫尔和米琼恩了
I can't find Merle or Michonne.
他们不见了
They've gone.
跟我来
Come on.
他刚才在这儿来着
He was in here.
说要找些毒品
Said he was looking for drugs.
其实他还说了很多事
Said a lot of things, actually.
比如呢
Like what?
他说你会改变主意
Said that you were gonna change your mind.
在这儿
Here we go.
看来他是把她从这儿带走的
Yeah, he took her here.
地上有痕迹
They mixed it up.
见鬼  我去追他
Damn it! I'm going after him.
-你不会追踪  -那我们一起去
- You can't track for shit. - Then the both of us.
不  我自己去
No, just me.
我之前就说过要去
I said I'd go and I'll go.
而且万一他们来袭
Plus they're gonna come back here.
你得做好准备
You need to be ready.
你家人也要做准备
Your family, too.
我想和我弟弟在一起
I want to be with my brother.
而我弟弟想留在监狱里
My brother, he wants to be in the prison.
我们这一趟
This little trip...
或许可以保全监狱
maybe it'll keep that place standing.
如果计划成功  或许我能获得原谅
If I pull it off, maybe all is forgiven.
太多的或许了
That's a whole lot of maybes.
我没有其他选择
You got to play the hands you're dealt.
只能一搏
I only got one.
你不停说自己有多重要
You talk about the weight of what you have to do,
干脏活有多伟大
how you can handle it.
但一个坏人
A bad man,
一个邪恶的人
someone truly evil,
他们轻如鸿毛
they're light as a feather.
没人在意
They don't feel a thing.
灾变后  我已经杀了十六个人
I've killed 16 men since all this went down.
走吧
Let's go.
看看那个混蛋都干了些什么
Look at what that bastard's done.
看看我们现在
Look at us.
他只是一个人
He's one man.
总会有这样的人
There'll be others like him.
向来如此
There always have been.
我知道  就像行尸一样
I know. It's like the walkers.
我们什么都改变不了
There's nothing we can do.
当你给我这个表时
When you gave me this...
我并不完全明白你的用意
I didn't fully understand what it meant.
其实很简单
Such a simple thing.
现在我明白了
I know what it means now.
明白了其中的责任
I know what it takes.
我要娶玛姬
I want to marry Maggie.
我们不用办婚礼
And we don't have to have a wedding.
我不知道我们能不能活过这周
I don't even know if we'll last the week.
但我想在
But I want her to know
生命结束之前
before...
让她知道
who knows?
我赞同  祝福你们
You have my blessing.
谢谢
Thank you.
好了
All right.
目前为止一切顺利
I think we're good.
呵呵
Yeah, we're great.
快点
Come on.
太好了
Yeah!
弄好了
That's the deal.
糟了
Oh, shit.
莫尔
Merle!
快点  莫尔
Come on, Merle!
莫尔
Merle!
好  好了
Okay. That's it.
来吧
Come on.
我们走
Let's go!
你的特长就是干脏活吗
So is this your thing, then? You take out the trash?
别这么刻薄  亲爱的
Don't be so hard on yourself, darlin'.
不管是总督  还是瑞克
The Governor, Rick,
只要有人的夜壶满了
anyone who needs their piss bucket emptied
你就抢着去倒
and you come a-running.
你弟弟就不一样了
Things are different for your brother.
没错  是不一样
Yeah, they are.
他唯瑞克马首是瞻
Rick says jump and he wants to know how high.
瑞克离不开他
Mm-mmm. Rick needs him.
敬重他
Respects him.
瑞克可没要求他干这活儿  对吧
He didn't ask him to do this little job, now, did he?
没  因为只有我能办妥
No, 'cause he wants it done.
你在自欺欺人
You keep telling yourself that.
事实上  这对你本是个大好机会
The truth is this could have been your shot.
凭你的本事  一个全新的开始
With your skills, a whole new beginning.
可惜你选择继续当个外人
But you choose to stay on the outside.
你死了没人会惦记
No one's gonna mourn you,
达里尔也不会
not even Daryl.
他现在有了个新家
He's got a new family.
你再试图惹怒我
You keep trying to get under my skin,
我就把你舌头割了
I'm gonna cut that tongue out.
瑞克把你交出去
Your buddy's turning you over
是为了自保
'cause he's trying to save his own ass.
你和我一样  都是外人  姑娘
You're as much on the outside as I am, girl.
也许吧
Maybe.
可等总督折磨死我
But once the Governor's done with me,
至少我不用苟活于世
at least I won't have to live with myself.
你说灾变后你杀了十六个人
You said you killed 16 men since this thing started?
灾变前你杀过人吗
You ever kill anyone before?
没有
No.
那到伍德伯里之前呢
And how about before Woodbury?
在你认识总督之前呢
Before you met him?
这么说  他救了你
So he saves your life,
给你吃穿
cleans you up,
给你洗脑
fed you a line of bullshit.
你为什么要给他当杀手
Why would you kill somebody else for him?
我们可以回去
You know, we can go back.
不可能
Ain't happening.
你和我
Both of us.
我们可以回去的
We can just go back.
我回不去
I can't go back.
你不明白吗
Don't you understand that?
我回不去了
I can't.
为什么
Why?
你回去找他们吧
You go back with them.
做好备战
Get ready for what's next.
我有点事要独自去办
I got something I got to do on my own.
我哥在哪儿
Where's my brother?
你把他杀了吗
You kill him?
他把我放了
He let me go.
别让他们找我
Don't let anyone come after me.
哪儿来的声音
Where's it coming from?
快  快  跟我来
Come on, come on. With me.
大家分头找
We'll have to spread out!
你俩跟我来
You two with me.
行尸
Walkers!
到处都是
All over!
在那儿
Hey, over there.
把他留给我
You leave him to me!
我不会求饶的
I ain't gonna beg.
我不会向你求饶
I ain't begging you.
好吧
No.
卡尔找你
Carl was looking for you.
他找到我了
He found me.
我们得回去  瑞克有事要说
I think we should head over. Rick has something to say.
那个
Uh, just...
还有件事
one more thing before that.
给你
Here.
我愿意
Yes.
我去见总督时
When I met with the Governor,
他提出一项协议
he offered me a deal.
他说
He said--
只要我交出米琼恩
he said he would leave us alone
他就不再骚扰我们
if I give him Michonne.
为了保证大家的安全
And I was gonna do that...
我本打算这么做
to keep us safe.
我改变了主意
I changed my mind.
但现在莫尔把米琼恩带去赴约
But now Merle took Michonne to fulfill the deal
而达里尔前去阻止他
and Daryl went to stop him
我不知道是否已经太迟了
and I don't know if it's too late.
我不该瞒着你们
I was wrong not to tell you.
对不起
And I'm sorry.
去年农场遇袭后的
What I said last year,
第一个晚上
that first night
我说过要独裁
after the farm...
我们不能那样
it can't be like that.
不能
It can't.
我们做什么  我们的底限
What we do, what we're willing to do,
我们是谁  这些不是我说了算
who we are, it's not my call.
永远不是
It can't be.
我不能为顾全大局牺牲我们当中任何一人
I couldn't sacrifice one of us for the greater good
因为我们每个人都是大局
because we are the greater good.
我们才是我们还活着的理由
We're the reason we're still here,
不是我个人
not me.
这事关生死
This is life and death.
你如何活着
How you live...
如何死去
how you die--
那不是我说了算
it isn't up to me.
我不是你们的总督
I'm not your Governor.
我们一起选择离开
We choose to go.
我们一起选择留下
We choose to stay.
我们团结一致
We stick together.
我们投票
We vote.
我们可以留下  可以战斗
We can stay and we can fight
也可以离开
or we can go.
不
No!